# UAN CARLOS CRUZ

# Junior Developer

+63 949 364 8547



jmcruz14.github.io



jcmcruz14@gmail.com



15 Narra Street, Project 3, Barangay Claro, Quezon City



## SUMMARY

As a team-oriented individual with a passion for building systems and understanding data science and analytics, I am excited to apply these skills as a data scientist. I hope to contribute to the company's mission by improving user experience, making data- driven design decisions, and providing strong soft skills to the company.

#### SKILLS

- Front-end & back-end web development
- UI/UX Testing & Evaluation
- Python, HTML/CSS, SQL (Postgres)
- · Database planning and design

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of the Philippines, Diliman

Bachelor's Degree in Industrial Engineering 2019 - 2022 Cum laude

- Data Science and Analytics
- · Source control via Git
- JS, Vue.js & popular Vue frameworks (NUXT, Quasar)
- Microsoft Office and other Project Management tools
- · Communication, adaptability, and a driven attitude

#### University of the Philippines, Los Baños

Bachelor's Degree in Industrial Engineering 2017 - 2019 Laude standing

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Junior Developer

MYCURE | April 2023 - December 2023

- Used Vue.js to make improvements in the Billing, Inventory, Medical Records, and other modules of the Clinic Management System
- Assisted in the improvements to internal and business-facing performance evaluation methods through better Sprint methodology and the creation of the Admin Dashboard via Metabase
- Contributed at least 20 feature implementations and bugfixes to the company's main product and helped close a company side project's first milestone

#### Full-stack Developer

UP National Engineering Center | June 2022 - December 2022

- Developed 8 modules and pages for an internal Budget Utilization DBMS using Python via the Dash Plotly framework
- Incorporated changes to both front-end (website) and back-end (database) using Python, SQL, and HTML/CSS.

#### Intern

Interactive Learning Center Diliman | February 2022 - July 2022

- Evaluated and provided suggestions on 5 prototype wire frame designs to be further developed for public use
- Provided voice-over for at least 20 training modules on how to use company- produced applications and systems for public use

#### CERTIFICATIONS

• Datacamp - Data Scientist Associate (May 2023)

# **PROJECTS**

- Capstone Project Route Optimizer Application for Last-Mile
  - Front-end application for a capstone partner which uses Python packages to process a list of locations to return
  - o Stack: Dash Plotly, Google Geocoder, MapQuest API

# most optimal delivery route

## ORGANIZATIONS

- · UP Data Science Society
- UP Industrial Engineering Club
- UP Junior Financial Association
- UP Debate Society

#### • Personal Projects

- Video Color Analyzer of Films
  - Python program which analyzes videos of any length and returns the 5 most frequent colors visible in the video
  - Stack: OpenCV-Python, Pillow, and other pertinent Python
- o <u>r/phr4r webscraper</u>
  - Webscraper built in 2022 to analyze a specific subreddit to achieve pertinent demographic analysis and other observations
  - Stack: pRAW, Openpyxl